Hey everybody and welcome to the
content video going over section
8.5 of the textbook changing
character case and this is actually
a really, really simple video
so we won't spend a ton of time
here, but there are three functions
I want you to be aware of.
So, let's say we have a
name, we'll use my name,
and here are the three
functions. So, I want you to
know about name.capitalize,
name.orstring.upper,
and string.lower.
And let me add a little
bit of commenting here.
and we're
just going to print each of these out.
Okay,
so let's, oh,
whoops,
got my parentheses again. Okay, now let's
take a look at them. Okay, so capitalize.
Notice how the string looks
exactly the same, Chelsea
Harding, except for the H on
my last name is now lowercase.
Upper, everything's in uppercase.
Lower, everything is in lowercase.
So the only one that really needs
some in-depth explaining here is
capitalize will change the first
character in your string to be a capital
letter and everything else to be a
lower letter or a lowercase letter.
Upper and lower get
we really use them when we're
doing like string cleaning where
we're looking for like let's say
like a user inputs their name and
capitalize but we want to see
if it matches any other cases of
their name in a data set. We
would convert everything to upper
or lowercase just so that we
can see if strings match without
necessarily having to doing any
other like checking on the string.
So just makes it nice and easy
because Python is case sensitive.
And so these functions
will help us a lot with
cleaning up strings and
things like that. So that's
all for this content
video. Thanks for watching.